in this video we will start
在这段视频中 我们将开始
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
to talk about a new version
介绍一种新的
of linear regression that's more powerful.
更为有效的线性回归形式
One that works with multiple variables
这种形式适用于多个变量
or with multiple features.
或者多特征量的情况
Here's what I mean.
比如说：
In the original version of
在之前我们学习过的
linear regression that we developed,
线性回归中
we have a single feature x,
我们只有一个单一特征量
the size of the house, and
房屋面积 x
we wanted to use that to
我们希望用这个特征量
predict why the price of
来预测
the house and this was
房子的价格
our form of our hypothesis.
这就是我们的假设
But now imagine, what if
但是想象一下
we had not only the size
如果我们不仅有房屋面积
of the house as a feature
作为预测房屋
or as a variable of which
价格的特征量
to try to predict the price,
或者变量
but that we also knew the
我们还知道
number of bedrooms, the number
卧室的数量
of house and the age of the home and years.
楼层的数量以及房子的使用年限
It seems like this would give
这样就给了我们
us a lot more information with which to predict the price.
更多可以用来
To introduce a little bit
预测房屋价格的信息
of notation, we sort of
先简单介绍一下记法
started to talk about this earlier,
我们开始的时候就提到过
I'm going to use the variables
我要用
X subscript 1 X subscript
x 下标1
2 and so on to
x 下标2  等等
denote my, in this
来表示
case, four features and I'm
这种情况下的四个特征量
going to continue to use
然后仍然用
Y to denote the variable,
Y来表示我们
the output variable price that we're trying to predict.
所想要预测的输出变量
Let's introduce a little bit more notation.
让我们来看看更多的表示方式
Now that we have four features
现在我们有四个特征量
I'm going to use lowercase "n"
我要用小写n
to denote the number of features.
来表示特征量的数目
So in this example we have
因此在这个例子中 我们的n等于4
n4 because we have, you
因为你们看 我们有
know, one, two, three, four features.
1 2 3 4 共4个特征量
And "n" is different from
这里的n和我们之前
our earlier notation where we
使用的n不同
were using "n" to denote the number of examples.
之前我们是用的“m”来表示样本的数量
So if you have
所以如果你有47行
47 rows  "M" is the
那么m就是这个表格里面的行数
number of rows on this table or the number of training examples.
或者说是训练样本数
So I'm also
然后我要用x 上标 (i)
going to use X superscript
来表示第i个
"I" to denote the
训练样本的
input features of the "I" training example.
输入特征值
X2 is going to
x上标 (2)
be a vector of
就是表示第二个
the features for my second training example.
训练样本的特征向量
And so X2 here is
因此这里
going to be a vector 1416,
x(2)就是向量 [1416, 3, 2, 40]
3, 2, 40 since those
因为这四个数字对应了
are my four
我用来预测房屋价格的
features that I have
第二个房子的
to try to predict the price of the second house.
四个特征量
So, in this notation, the
因此在这种记法中
superscript 2 here.
这个上标2
That's an index into my training set.
就是训练集的一个索引
This is not X to the power of 2.
而不是x的2次方
Instead, this is, you know,
这个2就对应着
an index that says look at the second row of this table.
你所看到的表格中的第二行
This refers to my second training example.
即我的第二个训练样本
With this notation X2 is
x上标(2) 这样表示
a four dimensional vector.
就是一个四维向量
In fact, more generally, this is
事实上更普遍地来说
an in-dimensional feature back there.
这是n维的向量
subscript J to denote
下标j
the value of the J,
来表示
of feature number J
第i个训练样本的
and the training example.
第j个特征量
So concretely X2 subscript 3,
因此具体的来说
will refer to feature
x上标(2)下标3代表着
number three in the
第2个训练样本里的第3个特征量
x factor which is equal to 2,right?
对吧？
That was a 3 over there, just fix my handwriting.
这个是3 我写的不太好看
So x2 subscript 3 is going to be equal to 2.
所以说x上标(2)下标3就等于2
Now that we have multiple features,
既然我们有了多个特征量
let's talk about what the
让我们继续讨论一下
form of our hypothesis should be.
我们的假设形式应该是怎样的
Previously this was the
这是我们之前使用的假设形式
form of our hypothesis, where x
x就是我们唯一的特征量
was our single feature, but
但现在我们有了多个特征量
now that we have multiple features,
我们就不能再
we aren't going to use the simple representation any more.
使用这种简单的表示方式了
Instead, a form
取而代之的
of the hypothesis in linear regression
我们将把线性回归的假设
is going to be this, can be
改成这样
theta 0 plus theta
θ0加上
1 x1 plus theta 2
θ1 乘以 x1 加上
x2 plus theta 3 x3
θ2乘以x2 加上 θ3 乘以x3
plus theta 4 X4.
加上θ4乘以x4
And if we have N features then
然后如果我们有n个特征量
rather than summing up over
那么我们要将所有的n个特征量相加
our four features, we would have
而不是四个特征量
a sum over our N features.
我们需要对n个特征量进行相加
Concretely for a particular
举个具体的例子
setting of our parameters we
在我们的设置的参数中
may have H of
我们可能有h(x)等于
X 80 + 0.1 X1 +  0.01x2 + 3x3 - 2x4.
80 + 0.1 x1 + 0.01x2 + 3x3  -  2x4
This would be one
这就是一个
example of a hypothesis
假设的范例
and you remember a
别忘了
hypothesis is trying to predict
假设是为了预测
the price of the house in
大约以千刀为单位的房屋价格
thousands of dollars, just saying
就是说
that, you know, the base
一个房子的价格
price of a house
可以是
is maybe 80,000 plus another open
80 k加上
1, so that's an extra,
0.1乘以x1
what, hundred dollars per square feet,
也就是说 每平方尺100美元
yeah, plus the price goes up
然后价格
a little bit for each
会随着楼层数的增加
up further for each additional
随着卧室数的增加
bedroom the house has, because
因为x3是
X three was the number
卧室的数量
of bedrooms, and the price
但是呢
goes down a little bit
房子的价格会
with each additional age of the house.
随着使用年数的增加
With each additional year of the age of the house.
而贬值
Here's the form of a hypothesis rewritten on the slide.
这是重新改写过的假设的形式
And what I'm gonna do is
接下来
introduce a little bit of
我要来介绍一点
notation to simplify this equation.
简化这个等式的表示方式
For convenience of notation, let
为了表示方便
me define x subscript 0 to be equals one.
我要将x下标0的值设为1
Concretely, this means that for
具体而言 这意味着
every example i I
对于第i个样本
have a feature vector X superscript
都有一个向量x上标(i)
I and X superscript
并且x上标(i)
I subscript 0 is going to be equal to 1.
下标0等于1
You can think of this as defining
你可以认为我们
an additional zero feature.
定义了一个额外的第0个特征量
So whereas previously I had
因此 我过去有n个特征量
n features because x1, x2
因为我们有x1 x2
through xn, I'm now defining
直到xn 由于我另外定义了
an additional sort of zero
额外的第0个特征向量
feature vector that always takes
并且它的取值
on the value of one.
总是1
So now my feature vector
所以我现在的特征向量x
X becomes this N+1 dimensional
是一个从0开始标记的
vector that is zero index.
n+1维的向量
So this is now a n+1
所以现在就是一个
dimensional feature vector, but
n+1维的特征量向量
I'm gonna index it from
但我要从0开始标记
0 and I'm also going
同时
to think of my
我也想把我的参数
parameters as a vector.
都看做一个向量
So, our parameters here, right
所以我们的参数就是
that would be our theta zero,
我们的θ0
theta one, theta two, and so
θ1 θ2 等等
on all the way up to theta n,
直到θn
we're going to gather
我们要把
them up into a parameter
所有的参数都写成一个向量
vector written theta 0, theta
θ0
1, theta 2, and so
θ1 θ2
on, down to theta n.
直到θn
This is another zero index vector.
这里也有一个从0开始标记的矢量
It's of index signed from zero.
下标从0开始
That is another n plus 1 dimensional vector.
这是另外一个
So, my hypothesis cannot be
所以我的假设
written theta 0x0 plus
现在可以写成θ0乘以x0
theta 1x1+ up to
加上θ1乘以x1直到
theta n Xn.
θn 乘以xn
And this equation is
这个等式
the same as this on
和上面的等式是一样的
top because, you know,
因为你看
eight zero is equal to one.
x0等于1
Underneath and I now
下面 我要
take this form of the
把这种形式假设等式
hypothesis and write this
写成
as either transpose x,
θ转置乘以X
depending on how familiar
取决于你对
you are with inner products of
向量内积有多熟悉
vectors if you
如果你展开
write what theta transfers x
θ转置乘以X
is what theta transfer and
那么就得到
this is theta zero,
θ0
theta one, up to theta
θ1直到θn
N. So this
这个就是θ转置
thing here is theta transpose
实际上
and this is actually a N
这就是一个
plus one by one matrix.
n+1乘以1维的矩阵
It's also called a row vector
也被称为行向量
and you take that and
用行向量
multiply it with the
与X向量相乘
vector X which is X
X向量是
zero, X one, and so
x0 x1等等
on, down to X n.
直到xn
And so, the inner product
因此内积就是
that is theta transpose X
θ转置乘以X
is just equal to this.
就等于这个等式
This gives us a convenient way
这就为我们提供了一个
to write the form of the
表示假设的
hypothesis as just the inner
更加便利的形式
product between our parameter
即用参数向量θ以及
vector theta and our theta
特征向量X的内积
vector X. And it
这就是改写以后的
is this little bit of notation,
表示方法
this little excerpt of the
这样的表示习惯
notation convention that let
就让我们
us write this in this compact form.
可以以这种紧凑的形式写出假设
So that's the form of a hypthesis when we have multiple features.
这就是多特征量情况下的假设形式
And, just to give this another
起另一个名字
name, this is also
就是
called multivariate linear regression.
所谓的多元线性回归
And the term multivariable that's just
多元一词
maybe a fancy term for saying
也就是用来预测的多个特征量
we have multiple features, or
或者变量
multivariables with which to try to predict the value Y.
就是一种更加好听的说法罢了